[{"question":"41. During pregnancy corpus luteum: ","a":"(a) Degenerates","b":" (b) Changes to corpus albicans ","c":"(c) Persists until parturition ","d":"(d) Persists upto the middle of pregnancy  ","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"42. Blood calcium levels are maintained because the bones act as a calcium sink in which calcium can either be stored or procured based on the body's needs. If a person secretes too much parathyroid hormone (one possible factor in the bone disease osteoporosis), What happens to  calcium levels in the body? ","a":"(a) Bone stores are depleted and the kidneys move calcium.","b":"(b) Bone stores are depleted and the kidneys retain calcium.","c":"(e) Blood levels of calcium may read high. ","d":" (d) Both (b) and (c)","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"43. The graph below illustrates the changes in blood sugar concentration after a healthy man has drunk a glucose solution.  300-  200-  1004 1000  time/h  Which one of the following graphs would apply to a diabetic man in similar circumstances?  glucose/mg 100 cm blood","a":"3004  200-  (a) 100  0","b":"3004  200-  100  (b)","c":"300-  200-  100%  00  (c)","d":"300-  200-  100  0  (d)","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"44. Which of the following does not secrete any hormone?","a":"(a) Spleen ","b":"(b) Ovary ","c":" (e) Testes","d":"(d) Pancreas","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"45. 'Brain sand' is associated to: ","a":"(a) Pineal body ","b":"(b) Thymus gland ","c":" (c) Thyroid gland","d":" (d) Pituitary gland","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"46. The given figure is related with principal endocrine glands in human. Identify 1 to 7.","a":"(a) 1- Pineal, 2- Pituitary, 3- Thyroid and parathyroid, 4- Thymus, 5- Adrenal, 6- Testis, 7- Ovary","b":"(b) 1- Pituitary, 2- Pineal, 3- Thyroid and parathyroid, 4-Thymus, 5-Adrenal, 6- Ovary, 7- Testis","c":"(c) 1- Pituitary, 2- Pineal, 3- Thyroid and parathyroid, 4- Thymus, 5- Kidney, 6-Testis, 7- Ovary","d":"(d) 1- Pituitary, 2- Pineal, 3- Thyroid and parathyroid, 4-Thymus, 5- Adrenal, 6-Testis, 7- Ovary","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"47. Which of the following statement is correct regarding glucagon hormone?","a":"(a) It has opposite effect to that of insulin. ","b":"(b) converts glucose to glycogen. ","c":"(c) It is given to diabetic patients. ","d":"(d) It is formed by B-cells of pancreas.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"48. If both the ovaries of rat are removed then which of the following hormones will be deficient?","a":"(a) Prolactin ","b":"(b) Oestrogen","c":"(c) Oxytocin ","d":"(d) Gonadotrophic hormone","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"49. Which one is different from the category of other three?","a":"(a) Gastrin","b":"(b) Ptyalin","c":"(c) Secretin","d":"(d) Glucagon","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"50  . Match column-I with column-II and select the correct answer using the codes given below.  Column-I  Column-II  A.  B.  C.  Adenohypophysis  I  Epinephrine  Adrenal medulla  II. II.  Somatotropin  Parathyroid gland  III.  Thymosin  D. Thymus gland  IV. Calcitonin  .","a":"(a) A-III; B-I; C-IV; D-II ","b":" (b) A-1; B-II; C-III; D-IV","c":"(c) A - Pi B - I C - IV D - III ","d":"(d) A - IV B-III: C - Pi D - I","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"51. Antiageing hormone is:  ","a":"(a) Thyroxine","b":"(b) Melatonin","c":" (c) Estrogen","d":"(d) Testosterone","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"52. Which of the following statement(s) is/are correct?  Critical Thinking  (i) Maximum iodine is stored in thyroid gland.  (ii) Calcitonin is non-iodinised hormone secreted by parafollicular cells of thyroid gland.  (iii) Calcitonin (TCT) regulates the blood C * a ^ 2 level.  (iv) TCT is hypocalcemic factor.","a":"(a) All of these","b":"(b) None of these  ","c":"(c) (i), (ii) and (iii)","d":"(d) Only (iv) ","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"53. A decrease in the level of oestrogen and progesterone causes:","a":"(a) Growth and dilation of myometrium.  ","b":"(b) Growth of endometrium.","c":"(c) Constriction of uterine blood vessels leading to sloughing of endometrium or uterine epithelium.","d":"(d) Release of ovum from the ovary.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"54. Complete failure of the anterior lobe of pituitary causes:","a":"(a) Conn's disease","b":"(b) Acromegaly","c":"(c) Cushing's disease","d":"(d) Simmond's disease  ","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"55. If a person has protruding eyes, tachycardia and higher body temperature, he is suffering from:","a":"(a) Cretinism","b":"(b) Hyperthyroidism","c":"(c) Myxoedema","d":"(d) Acromegaly","hint":"","correct":"b"}]